- 哦，队长...-怎么了，队长？
- Oh, captain... - What is it, captain?
树林里全是阿尔巴尼亚人，你还想穿过去
The woods are full of Albanians and you want to go through.
你得服从上级，快点，站起来
You obey your superiors. Come on, on your feet.
必须有人为马契科夫而战
Somebody has to fight for Machkov kamen
你流了很多血，伤口太深了，你会死的
You've lost lot of blood. The wound is too deep. You'll die.
他们根本不在乎你
They don't give a shit about you, man.
来吧
Come on.
- 站起来 - 站起来！
- On your feet! - On your feet!
我不是警告过你别惹魔鬼吗？
Didn't I warn you not to mess with the devil?
- 把他裹在毯子里 - 你确定吗兄弟？
- Let's roll him in the blanket. - Are you sure about this, bro?
- 裁缝会发疯的 - 我才不管什么裁缝！
- Tailor will go mad. - I don't give a shit about Tailor!
来吧，把他的鞋穿上，我们带他去镇上
C'mon, put his shoes on and let's take him to the town.
不，不去镇上
No, not to the town.
带我去找普尔沙
Take me to Prsha.
天啊! 你为什么还要去找那个混蛋？
Jesus! Why do you want to go to that scumbag?
走吧！
C'mon, c'mon!
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第五集
Black Sun
基拉老板，你懂拉丁语吗？
Boss Kira, do you know Latin?
拉丁语? 不懂
Latin? No.
你是马其顿人，你懂希腊语吗？
You're Macedonian, do you know Greek?
- 是的 - 还有塞尔维亚语？
- Yes. - And Serbian?
- 也懂 - 很好
- That too. - Nice.
比起希腊人，我更喜欢罗马人
You see, I always preferred Romans to Greeks.
罗马人建立了一个伟大的帝国、立法系统、军团..
Romans built a great empire, legislative system, legions...
在某种程度上，他们也建造了这座城市
In a way, they built this city too. Greeks, on the other hand,
和年轻男人做爱，还有很多关于民主的屁话
shagged young boys and spoke a lot of shit about democracy.
但我相信你来这里不是为了研究
But I'm sure you didn't come here to study the differences
- 这些希腊人和罗马人之间差异 - 可以这么说
- between Greeks and Romans. - You could put it like that.
我猜你应该带来了商业提议吧？
I'm guessing you have a business proposal?
是的，没错
Yes. Indeed.
那么这个提议是否与
And could that proposal have something to do
监狱里的某个恐怖分子有联系？
with a certain terrorist in Glavnyacha prison?
他不是恐怖分子，他是个爱国者，一个自由斗士
He's not a terrorist, he's a patriot. A freedom fighter.
请原谅，我是个商人
Please forgive me. I'm a merchant.
我无法分辨这些差别
I can't tell all the nuances.
但是让我们回到我们的罗马人
But let us go back to our Romans.
Bellum omnium contra omnes
“所有人对所有人的战争”
"The war of all against all."
我不明白
I don't understand.
这正是你在贝尔格莱德想要做的
Well, that's exactly what you're trying to do here in Belgrade.
挑起一场全面战争
To provoke an all-out war.
我要我的人出狱
I want my man out of the prison.
当然
Of course.
他怎么能在监狱里为祖国而战呢？
How can he fight for his fatherland from jail?
- 这不可能 - 所以我们才要求帮助
- It's impossible. - That's why we asked for help.
他们会像宰畜生一样杀了他! 我们做个交易吧:
They'll shoot him like a dog! Let's make a bargain:
我们不计较那批被俄国人扣押的货物
We'll forget that shipment seized by Russians.
我们再免费赠送一批
And we'll give one more, for free.
- 还有呢 - 还有？
- And more. - And more?
你要什么？
Yes, more. How much do you want?
只是你生意中的一小部分
Just a modest share in your business.
分成? 不可能！
A percentage? No way!
凯罗老板
Boss Kyra...
看起来我们不太了解对方
Looks like we didn't understand each other.
当我提到战争时
When I mentioned the war,
你一定以为我反对战争
you must've thought I'm against it.
不，我喜欢战争
No. I like war.
但战争是昂贵的
But war is expensive.
- 15% - 20%
- Fifteen. - Twenty.
恭喜你，督察，我们现在可以喝白兰地了
Congratulations, inspector. We could have that brandy now.
谢谢你，你知道我上班时不喝酒的
Thank you. You know I don't drink on duty.
咖啡来了
Here's the coffee.
不了，不过还是谢谢你
No, but thanks anyway.
你们两个，跟我去监狱
You two, let's go to prison.
给你，督察
There you go, inspector.
扣上扣子，把咖啡拿走
Button up. Take that coffee away.
你不想说话
You don't want to talk.
你残忍地杀了两个人却无话可说
You brutally killed two people and you've got nothing to say.
让我们打他一顿吧，督察
Let us beat the crap out of him, inspector.
然后他就什么都说了
Then he'll sing like a bird.
听着 艾林... 没人在乎你这个瘾君子
Look, Avram... No one gives a damn about this junkie.
但对于国家检察官的妻子
But for the wife of the state prosecutor,
维奥莱塔 · 朱基奇来说
Violeta Djukich...
我可不想站在你的立场
I wouldn't want to be in your shoes.
- 别费嘴皮子了，让我们... - 别说话！
- Stop persuading him. Let us... - Cut it!
- 你死定了 - 你才死定了
- You're doomed. - You are doomed.
死亡的目的是复活
The purpose of dying is to rise from the dead.
变得更加强大
More powerful.
新时代即将来临
The new era is coming.
你不知道吗，年轻人？
Don't you know that, you little man?
而且，当新时代来临的时候，所有这一切都将毫无意义
And, when it happens, all of this will be meaningless.
我的牺牲，谋杀
My sacrifice, the murders.
我什么都见过了
I've seen it all.
在我的梦里，在我的画布上
In my dreams, on my canvases,
尤其是在被斩掉头颅的眼中
in the eyes of the beheaded. Especially there.
你们的文明正在消亡
Your civilisation is dying.
在新的世界秩序下
And in the new world order,
我不是罪犯，而是英雄
I won't be a criminal, but a hero.
这个世界将会投降
This world will surrender,
被选中的人将以铁腕统治
and chosen ones will rule with an iron fist.
- 你是天选之子? - 不是我
- And you're the chosen one? - Not me.
是我们！
Us!
我们无处不在
We're everywhere.
我们是一个军团
We're a legion.
你听过那个故事吗，年轻人？
Have you heard that story, little man?
他们来到海的另一边
"And they came to the other side of the sea,
”进入格拉森的国度
"into the country of the Gerasenes.
耶稣从船里走出来，从坟墓里迎接他们
"And when he came out of the boat, Out of the tombs to meet them
”来了一个被污灵附体的人
"came a man with an unclean spirit
耶稣大声喊着说、我与你何干呢
"and crying out with a loud voice, he saith, What have I to do with thee,
耶稣，至高神的儿子
Jesus, thou Son of the Most High God?"
他说:
And he saith:
“从这个人身上出来吧，你这不洁的灵魂”
"Come out of this man, you impure spirit."
并问道: “你叫什么名字?”
And asketh: "What is thy name?".
“我的名字是一群，因为我们人多势众”
"My name is Legion, for we are many."
那是什么，督察？
What was that, inspector?
圣经 马可福音
The Holy Bible. Gospel of Mark.
尼什基...？
Nishky...?
那个裁缝，他是什么人？
That Tailor, who is he?
一个战争英雄
A war hero.
他和坦科西奇一起服役
He served with Tankosich.
他说他看到坦科西奇扇了加夫里洛王子一个耳光
He says he saw when Tankosich slapped Gavrilo Printzip.
废话少说，尼什基
Cut the crap, Nishky.
他是杀人犯，但不是骗子
He's a murderer, but not a liar.
裁缝这个绰号是他应得的
He earned that nickname
因为他很会用刀子
'cause he's good with knives.
他以外科手术般的精准度割开人们的喉咙
He cuts people's throats with surgical precision
战后
After the war,
当国王抛弃退伍军人时
when the king turned his back on veterans,
他们中的一些人成为了被褥裁缝
some of them became quilt makers,
屠夫，警察，杂货商
butchers, coppers or grocers.
然后他变成了一个杀手
And he became a killer.
这是他唯一擅长的事情
It was the only thing he was good at.
他的老板是谁？
And his boss? Who is he?
他的老板有两个名字，贫民窟里没有人敢提起
He has two names that no one in the slum dares to mention.
第一个是魔鬼，另一个是基督徒
The first one is diabolic, the other one is Christian.
你看，米兰，这是一个僧侣墓地
You see, Milan, this is a monk cemetery.
- 很有意思 - 是啊
Very interesting. Yeah.
第一次世界大战后我来到贝尔格莱德
When I came to Belgrade after the Great War,
我做的第一件事就是买下这块地
the first thing I did was to buy this land.
你知道为什么吗？
Do you know why?
我不知道，老板
I wouldn't know, boss.
我希望有一天能修复这座修道院
I want to restore this monastery one day.
我们的中世纪统治者是伟大的缔造者
Our medieval rulers were great founders.
这就是塞尔维亚到处都是教堂和修道院的原因
That's why Serbia is full of churches and monasteries.
他们活着的时候犯了各种各样的罪
They committed all kinds of sins while they were alive.
兄弟相残，父子相残，反之亦然
Brothers killed brothers, fathers killed sons, and vice versa.
然而，他们都成了圣人
And yet, they all became saints.
老板，你不是想成为圣人吗？
Boss, you want to become a saint, don't you?
总有一天，这里会有一座新的教堂
One day, there will be a new church here.
但是在我建立我的文化遗产之前，我需要去赢得它
But before I build my heritage, I need to earn it.
所以，我不得不承认更多的罪过，米兰
So, I have to commit many more sins, Milan.
你给我带来了什么？
What have you got for me?
你确定这次是真的吗？
Are you sure they're real this time?
我用我的生命担保
I guarantee it with my life.
谁的生命? 你的？
Whose life? Yours?
- 如果有必要的话 - 很有可能，米兰
- If necessary. - It may well be, Milan.
很有可能
It may well be.
呃... 那个... 我们杀了一个人
Erm.. Yes... We had to kill someone.
- 这算什么新鲜事? - 那个警察
- Well, what else is new? - Well, the cop.
我必须杀了那个警察
I had to kill that cop.
我别无选择
I had to. I had no choice.
你没有考虑到他是个警官吗？
The fact that he was an officer gave you a choice.
是的，但是我... 我必须这么做
Yes, but I just... I had to.
好吧，事已至此
Okay, what's done is done.
低调一段时间，在这事过去之前不要露面
Lay low for a while and don't go out until this passes.
好的，老板
Okay, boss.
- 还有，米兰... - 什么事？
- And Milan... - Yes?
赶快离开那个贫民窟吧
Get out of that slum already.
好的，老板
I will, boss.
难道你看不出来它会给你带来厄运吗？
Can't you see it brings you bad luck?
下午好，局长
Good afternoon, commissioner.
恭喜! 干得好！
Congratulations! Well done!
我想打电话给一些政客，炫耀我们的工作成果
I want to call some politicians. We've got something to brag about.
可以等等
It can wait.
犯罪嫌疑人需要紧急精神病学评估
The suspect needs an urgent psychiatrical evaluation.
- 我们有的是时间 - 这事很紧急，相信我
- We have all the time in the world. - It's urgent, believe me.
- 他疯了吗? - 毫无疑问
- Is he crazy? - Without a doubt.
每个人被逼到墙角的时候都是疯子
Everyone's crazy when they're put against the wall.
没错，但这个人不是演戏
Indeed. But this one isn't acting.
好的，我们会给他做检查
Okay. We'll have him examined.
进一步的调查方向取决于精神病评估结果
Further investigation depends on that examination.
塔尼在吗？
Is Tane around?
我们走！
Let's go!
- 乔洛维奇 - 塔纳西耶维奇... 他在哪儿？
- Mr. Djolovich - Tanasiyevich... Where is he?
他一整天都没出现
He didn't show up all day.
这是什么地方，警察局还是妓院？
What is this place, police station or a brothel?
塔纳西耶维奇昨天有急事
Tanasiyevich was in a hurry yesterday.
他有一项重要的任务
He had an important assignment.
- 今天他可能在休息 - 这位是..
- Today he's probably resting. - And that is...
我们年轻的同事，普莱蒂科西奇
Our young colleague Pletikosich.
他昨天逮捕了第一个犯罪嫌疑人
He made his first arrest yesterday.
看来维奥莱塔 · 朱基奇的案子已经破了
It seems like Violeta Djukich's case is solved.
破了…
Solved...
你想见嫌疑犯吗？
Knock on wood. Do you want to see the suspect?
去见嫌疑犯? 去你妈的！
To see the suspect? Go fuck yourselves!
再见，局长
Good bye, commissioner.
- 你们结婚多久了? - 太久了，小姐！
- How long you've been married? - Too long, miss!
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
十年左右
Ten years or so.
看起来你们从第一天起就相爱了
Looks like you loved each other from the day one.
那是什么意思? 好像人们不能在相处五年之后
What does that mean? As if people can't become
更加迷恋对方，爱情不会出现在彼此赤身裸体时
more infatuated after five years. It's not love when you strip naked,
而是在彼此赤裸裸地展现灵魂时，你受过良好的教育
but when you lay bare your soul. You have all that education,
但你什么都不懂，你妈妈没教过你吗？
and you don't know anything. Didn't your mom teach you?
她在我六岁的时候去世了
She died when I was six.
普尔沙！
Prsha!
- 普尔沙! 是塔妮! - 天啊，我不是告诉过你
- Prsha! It's Tane! - Jesus, haven't I told you
- 我不想见你 - 天啊！他还活着吗？
- I don't want to see you. - My God, is he alive?
- 能听到我说话吗? 发生什么事了? - 你是谁？
- Can you hear me? What happened? - Who is this?
我是玛雅，玛雅 · 达维多维奇，是你叫我来这里的
Maya, Maya Davidovich. You sent me here.
你可以回去了，他们不会再找你麻烦
You can go back now. They won't touch you.
他们已经得到了他们想要的
They got what they wanted.
你也是，快点，把他弄进去
And so did you. C'mon, get him inside.
洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
我不喜欢，他们人太多了
I don't like it. There are too many of them.
当然，这是他们的城市
But of course. It's their town.
他们用一辆装甲车载着他
They drive him in an armoured car.
两个警察在前面，两个在后面
Two cops in the front, two in the back.
- 还有六个人护送他们 - 骑自行车
- And six more escorting them. - On their bikes.
那监狱呢？
What about the prison?
最好的观察点在市场
The best view is from the market.
但是市场里到处都是人
But it is full of people.
- 这对我们有好处 - 也许没有
- It can be good for us. - Or not.
那里面呢？
What about the inside?
我可以弄到地图，但我们得贿赂一些人
I can get a map, but we'll have to grease somebody's palm.
去做吧，钱不是问题
Do it. Money is not an issue.
- 你要回布科沃了 - 为什么？
- You're going back to Bukovo. - Why is that?
我希望你带来新货物，还有她
I want you to bring new goods. And her.
- 她? - 是的，她
- Her? - Yes, her.
- 会很棘手的，老板 - 我知道
- It'll be very tricky, Boss Kyra. - I know.
但这不是你的问题
But that's not your problem.
快去吧！
C'mon, beat it!
他妈的！
Fuck this!
我还不如去卖南瓜籽
I better sell pumpkin seeds than opium.
我可以靠它发财
I would make fortune on it.
不要误会我的意思，瑞士是一个美妙的国家
Don't get me wrong. Switzerland is a wonderful country.
我甚至觉得我喜欢那里
I even think I liked it there.
但我对瑞士有一个奇怪的印象
But I got a strange impression
瑞士人除了生孩子、吃饭、睡觉、喝酒、工作什么都不干
that Swiss do nothing but procreate, eat, sleep, drink, work,
- 最后无聊的死去 - 而我们的孩子..
- and, in the end, die out of boredom. - While our children...
没有东西吃，没有地方睡觉，我说的对吗？
have nothing to eat and nowhere to sleep, am I right?
- 干杯 - 我们确实有目标
- Cheers. - Well, we do have a goal here.
我们在为一个更好的未来而奋斗
We're fighting for a better future.
是的
Yes.
我是说你和我
I mean you and I.
像我们这样的人
And people like us.
我们得把这个国家变成瑞士
I mean, we have to turn this country into Switzerland,
人们会因无聊而死的地方
the place where people would die out of boredom.
你真的认为我们的孩子会因为无聊而死吗？
You really think our children will die just out of boredom?
如果是你和我的孩子，会的，我想会的
If you and I make them, yeah, I think so.
你凭什么认为我想和你生孩子？
What makes you think I'd want to have babies with you?
你刚才说”我们的孩子”
You just said "our children".
哦，那只是一种比喻
Yes. It was a figure of speech.
- 比喻? - 是的
- A figure of speech? - Yes.
你要知道
And just so you know,
我对那些与生殖有关的活动并不陌生
I'm no stranger to these procreation-related activities.
- 真的吗?-是的
- Oh, really? - Yes.
如果你对此有意见，而且认为我是二手货
If you have a problem with that, and you think I'm damaged goods,
那你可以走了，我来买单
you're free to go. I'll pay the bill.
没关系，真的
It's okay, really.
博雅纳，我是一个有现代理念的人
Boyana, I'm a man of modern convictions.
在我已经有过性经验的情况下
It would be unfair to expect that you're a virgin...
期望你是处女是不公平的
when I'm not.
哦... 好吧
Oh... Well...
很高兴听到你有一些经验
It's nice to hear that you do have some experience.
这是不是意味着我今晚还有机会？
Does that mean I still have a chance tonight?
也不尽然
Not really.
我想也是
So I thought.
但我非常欣赏你让我改变主意的努力
But I'll immensely enjoy your efforts to make me change my mind.
我觉得我们进展得不太顺利
I see it's not going too well.
但是让我来帮你
But let me help you.
我要带你去一个地方
I'm taking you to a place
让我看到你真正的本性
where you can show me your real nature.
- 好吗? - 好
- Deal? - Deal.
斯米利亚，我得承认
Smilya, I must admit...
我不知道塔纳西耶维奇警官是你哥哥
I didn't know inspector Tanasiyevich is your brother.
我们不常见面，我都快忘了我还有个哥哥
We see each other so often that even I forget it.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
他为了保护我才被打
He was beaten up trying to protect me.
你以为你是唯一一个害被他打的人？
You think you're the only one he took a beating for?
这个傻瓜总是为了别人而毁了自己的生活
This fool keeps ruining his life for someone else.
就好像除了他之外没人能解决问题一样
Like there's no one else to mend things.
把白兰地递给我
Pass me the brandy.
最后，他进了警察局
Finally, he ended up in police.
简直是想找死
You'd say he has a death wish.
我所能做的就只有把他缝起来
All I can do is stitch him up
然后准备葬礼
and prepare for the funeral.
他没有家人吗？
Doesn't he have a family?
老婆孩子？
A wife, kids?
上帝没有保佑我们有孩子
God didn't bless us with children.
在这个不安稳的年代…
These heavy times...
至于妻子，他已经结婚了，不幸的是
As for the wife, he was married. Unfortunately.
亲爱的！
Andro, dear!
你最好再昏过去，这样就不会那么痛了
You better pass out again, it'll hurt less.
你为什么要醒过来？
Why did you have to wake up?
你的大嘴巴会让死人复活的
Your blabbing would raise the dead.
你为什么要偷我的肉？
Why did you steal meat from me?
你从那份中做了十个烤肉串，五个人吃
You made ten kebabs out of the portion for five.
肉串只有这么小
They were this tiny.
如果不是我，你根本不知道什么是烤肉串
If it wasn't for me, you wouldn't know what a kebab is.
也许是你看了裤裆才知道的
Maybe by looking in your underpants.
我学到的唯一一件事就是不要和一个蠢货同住一个酒馆
The only thing I learned was not to share a tavern with a twat.
我过河的时候在想什么？
What was I thinking when I crossed the river?
如果你问我的话，我会说，如果你淹死了会更好
It'd have been better if you had drowned, if you ask me.
- 没错 - 他醒了
- Indeed. - He's awake.
- 感谢上帝 - 为他的健康干杯！
- Thank you, sweet Jesus. - To his health!
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
别这样，放松点，别这么拘谨
C'mon, relax. Don't be so stiff.
请来两杯伏特加
Two vodkas, please.
亲爱的医生
Dear doctor.
祝你健康
To your health.
来吧，斯坦科，放松一点! 这是什么？
C'mon, Stanko, relax a bit! What is this?
教授！
Professor!
我看得出你已经就位了
I can see you're in position.
安提奇博士
Dr. Antich.
你真是秀色可餐
You're a real eye candy.
告诉我，你为什么带这个笨蛋来？
Tell me, why did you bring this plonker?
他让这地方看起来没那么俗气了
He's making this place look less cheesy.
别对他这么严厉，教授，我们会治好他的，不是吗
Don't be so hard on him, professor. We'll fix him up, alright.
在你宠坏我之前，我也是个“笨蛋”
I was a "plonker" too 'till you spoiled me.
你还没被宠坏呢
You ain't spoiled yet.
- 才不是 - 是的，是的
- No. - Yes, yes.
- 你这么认为? - 是的
- You think so? - Yes.
好了，教授，放松点
Alright, professor, take it easy.
- 我开得太快了 - 我也可以开得很快
- Oh, I've been going too fast. - I can do fast.
你的徒弟走了
There goes your apprentice.
阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇先生
Mr. Alimpiye Mirich.
我很高兴你这么快就来了
I'm glad you came on such a short notice.
问题是，我该怎么说呢？
The matter is rather, how should I put it?
- 紧急? - ”微妙”更合适，白兰地？
- Urgent? - "Delicate" is more adequate. Brandy?
我喜欢苏打水，不过水就可以了
I prefer soda. But the water would be just fine.
这次我们需要一个女孩，一个白人女孩
This time we need a girl. A white girl.
你受够吉普赛人了？
You're fed up with Gypsies?
拉贾奇基先生非常喜欢你
Mister Rajachki is very fond of you.
他认为这是有原因的
He thinks there's a good reason for that.
他还认为你的声誉是合理的
He also believes your reputation is justified.
那是什么样的声誉？
And what kind of reputation is that?
他认为这是有原因的
He believes there is a good reason for that.
他们说你是个言而有信的人，谢谢
They say you are a man of his word. Thank you.
并且还能做到守口如瓶
And the man who can keep his mouth shut.
我必须承认，你是对的，我充满了矛盾
I must admit, you are right. I'm full of contradictions.
正如你们塞尔维亚人喜欢说的，管好你们自己的事吧
As you Serbs like to say, mind your own business.
真的吗？
Really?
但是我们也有句俗话说: 明确的协议，朋友
But we also say: clear agreements, good friends.
说到安排，伯爵先生
Speaking of arrangements, Mr. Count,
我想你应该很清楚
I think you're well aware that certain favours
- 不能用钱来支付 - 你说得对，阿里姆皮耶
- cannot be paid with money. - You're quite right, Alimpiye.
这就是为什么我们的合同包括一项
That's why our arrangement includes a special agreement
关于“Hymdalpharm”的特别条款
with "Hymdalpharm", in case you forgot.
但提醒你一下
But in case you forgot,
这些东西很撤出来，我们两次脱身
these things are hard to pull out. We got away with - twice,
但现在风险更高了,
but now, the risk is higher,
代价也是如此
and so is the price.
好吧，这次你想要什么？
Alright. What do you want this time?
当然，除了钱以外？
Beside money, of course?
先生们，我很高兴地通知你们
Gentlemen, I have a great pleasure to inform you
很快我就会成为一家公司的老板
that soon I'll be the owner of a company
在罂粟交易中享有特权
with privileges in poppy seeds trade.
这就意味着
And that means:
在这个国家，所有鸦片
The entire trade of opium
和鸦片衍生物的交易
and opium derivatives, on the territory of the Kingdom
都在我的控制之中
will be under my control.
这就是为什么我需要和"Hymdalpharm"
Which is why I'll need much bigger, and better contract
签一个更好的合同
with "Hymdalpharm".
如果是那样的话，你的青睐
In that case, your favour will be regarded
将被视为善意的表示
as a gesture of good will,
“ Hymdalpharm”的所有者将给你合理的回报
and the owners of "Hymdalpharm" will know how to repay it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我会尽力的
I will do my best.
伯爵先生对以前的货物从未有过任何抱怨
Mr. Count never had any complaints about the previous shipments.
- 干杯 - 干杯！
- Cheers! - Cheers!
告诉我，伙计，谁在照看你的大麻？
Tell me, man, who is looking after your joint?
问倒我了，谁在照顾你的孩子？
Beats me. Who's lookin' after yours?
没人，伙计，我的生意完蛋了，没人付钱
No one, man. My business is ruined. Nobody pays anything.
他们只会用剃刀互相割伤
They're just cutting each other with razors.
都是卡拉德约杰维奇王朝的错，他们这些人渣！
Karadjordjevich dynasty is to blame, them scumbags!
去他妈的! 我还因为他们进了监狱，一无所获！
Fuck it, man! I was in jail because of them. For nothing!
他们砸我的窗户
They're smashing my windows.
- 你知道他们对我说什么吗? - 什么？
- You know what they say to me? - What?
说我是个告密者，警察的女婿
That I'm a snitch, a copper's son in law.
女婿那部分是真的，但是告密者？
Well, that son in law part is true. But a snitch?
- 别提了 - 最好别提
- Don't even mention it. - I better not.
嘿，尼什基! 你一整天都去哪儿了？
Hey, Nishky! Where've you been all day?
你管我去哪儿了？
What do you care where where have I been?
亲爱的上帝! 我们喝得烂醉如泥
Dear Lord! We're drunk as a skunk.
- 再见... - 好的，再见
- We are... - Okay, cheers, mate. See you.
好冷，生火，生火！
It's cold. Make a fire. Make a fire!
生火，士兵! 斯托扬有火种
Make a fire, soldier! Stoyan has tinder.
- 塔纳西耶维奇! 醒醒! - 索尼娅! 索尼娅！
- Tanasiyevich! Wake up! - Sonya! Sonya!
醒醒，索尼娅不在这，你在胡言乱语
Wake up! There's no Sonya here. You're raving.
醒醒! 醒醒! 一切都很好
Wake up! Wake up! Everything is alright.
你在这里干什么? 你为什么不在贝尔格莱德？
What you're doing here? Why aren't you in Belgrade?
我会一直待到你好起来，你先暖和起来
I'll stay 'till you get well. You got to warm up.
- 下雪了 - 斯米利亚！
- It's snowing. - Smilya!
死在雪地里最好了
It's best to die in the snow.
- 达米安，放开你自己 - 他怎么了？
- Damyan, just let yourself go. - What's the matter with him?
你怎么这么久才来? 他冷得像尸体一样
What took you so long? He's as cold as a corpse.
- 带点热的食物来! - 我去做汤
- Bring something warm and salty! - I'll make a soup.
快，给他搓搓身子！
C'mon, rub his skin!
振作起来，督察
Pull yourself together, inspector.
你会毁了我的名声的，没有人在我这边会表现得这么冷漠
You'll ruin my reputation. No one remained cold by my side.
索尼娅，去找你的孩子，去找你的孩子，索尼娅…
Sonya, go to your children. Go to your children, Sonya...
看他
Look at him;
帅气，英俊，还有须后水
nice, good-looking nice perfume...
你为什么不给自己找个好女人呢？
Why don't you find yourself a nice lady?
我不想宠坏她
Don't want to spoil her.
你会的，我已经被宠坏了，管他呢
And you're thinking, I'm already spoiled so what the hell.
你可以找个少妇呀
You could screw married women.
我不想破坏别人的婚姻
I don't want to ruin marriages.
你不会遇到很多女人…
You won't see many a pussy...
- 你这么认为? - 是的
- You think so? - I know so.
调查进行得怎么样了？
How's the investigation going?
- 我逮捕了一个杀人犯 - 我在问你我的案子
- I arrested a murderer. - I'm asking you about my case, man.
情况不妙
Not good.
你问过那个人的名字了吗？
Did you ask your Stavra about that man's name?
不，我不敢问他
No. I'm afraid to ask him.
- 你想让我问吗? - 什么都别问
- Do you want me to ask? - Don't ask anyone anything.
不管问出来没有，我都会受到惩罚
I would suffer the consequences, one way or another
那孩子叫什么名字？
And what's the boy's name?
- 佩塔尔 - 佩塔尔
- Petar. - Petar.
纵容那个无名的混蛋
To indulge that nameless piece of shit.
我记得，佩塔尔是他父亲的名字
I remembered, that was his father's name.
这是个很好的线索，玛拉！
That's a great clue, Mara!
- 什么? - 是的
- Say what? - Yes.
我们不用再一个无名的有钱人
We're no longer looking for a nameless rich man...
对
Right.
而是一个父亲叫佩塔尔的有钱人
But a rich guy whose father's name is Petar.
你会找到我儿子吗？
You're going to find my son?
我会的，我保证
I will. I promise.
留下过夜吧
Spend the night here.
至少一次
At least once.
我会的
I will.
托波尼卡 塞尔维亚
TOPONICA, SERBIA
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS AND SLOVENES
陛下，阿瓦库莫维奇博士来了
Your majesty, Dr. Avakumovich is here.
1924年 贝尔格莱德
1924. THE BORROUGH OF TOPCHIDER, CITY OF BELGRADE,
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS AND SLOVENES
塔纳西耶维奇！
Tanasiyevich!
你现在开心了吗？
Are you happy now?
陛下
Your Prince Highness...
我们别无选择
we didn't have a choice.
逮捕你们的战时指挥官！
Arresting your wartime commander!
- 你不觉得羞耻吗? - 对不起，陛下
- Aren't you ashamed? - I'm sorry, Your Highness.
对不起个屁，你这个叛徒！
Sorry my ass, you traitorous cunt!
我哥哥用一点零钱就把你们都收买了！
My brother bought all of you for a small change!
米利萨夫
Milisav.
你要干什么？
What do you want?
滚开！
Fuck off!
日夫科维奇
Zhivkovich...
我就知道你是幕后黑手
I knew you were behind this.
- 陛下... - 没跟你说话！
- Your Majesty... - Nobody asked you anything!
你他妈的死基佬! 我会用我的生命毁了你！
You fucking faggot! I'll dedicate my life to ruining you!
什么生命？
What life?
你已经是个死人了
You don't have a life anymore.
你为什么盯着那个西红柿，我的朋友？
Why are you staring at that tomato, my friend?
你要和它结婚吗? 要么买，要么离开
Are you going to marry it? Buy it or leave it.
- 你管这个叫西红柿? - 是的
- You call this a tomato? - Yes.
在马其顿，这都没樱桃大
In Macedonia, this wouldn't qualify as a cherry.
那么，你去马其顿买吧
Well, go to Macedonia and buy some.
你没有任何损失
It'll cost you nothing.
如果我在这里卖这些东西，我很快就发家致富了
If I were to sell these here, I'd be a rich man.
他们人太多了，老大
There are too many of them, boss.
他们就像蟑螂一样
They are like cockroaches.
如果打起来的话会有很多人，但现在不打
Too many if they fight, but not now.
好的，这里有30升红酒
Okay. Here you have 30 litre of red wine,
20升杜松白兰地
20 litre of juniper brandy,
还有10升李子白兰地放在地下室
and 10 litre of plum brandy. Put it in the basement.
千万别热了，这是玫瑰红葡萄酒
It mustn't get warm. And here is rosé.
13瓶乘以2，就是32
Now, 13 bottles times 2, that's 32.
还有20升杜松白兰地
And 20 litre of juniper brandy.
15块，加上李子和杜松白兰地
15, plus plum and juniper brandy...
56 x 2等于126，再加上13 x 3
Okay. 56 x 2 is 126, plus 13 x 3,
还有这个酒桶
and this barrel.
- 总共467第纳尔50分 - 多少？
- Total: 467 dinars and 50 cents. - How much?
给我467
Give me 467.
50分不要了，你给我来5个烤肉串
Screw the 50, you can give me five kebabs.
尼什基，过来！
Nishky, come here!
这是420
Here's 420.
- 我说的就是这些! - 你这个强盗！
- That's exactly what I've said! - You marauder...
来盘豆子，不要香肠
Beans without sausage.
- 你是素食主义者吗? - 不，我是马其顿人
- Are you a vegetarian? - No. Macedonian.
给我一张纸和一支笔
Give me a piece of paper and a pen.
听着，我要离开一段时间
Listen, I won't be here for a while.
如果有人问起，就说你没见过我
If anyone asks, you haven't seen me.
- 清楚了吗 - 是的
- Is that clear. - Yes.
你去哪儿了? 为什么迟到？
Where were you? Why are you late?
我刚去检查我的工人
I was checking up on my workers.
老板要你给他找个漂亮女人
The boss wants you to find him a pretty chick.
今晚把她送到这个地址，找个人帮你读
Deliver her to this address tonight. Find someone to read it for you.
听好了，你这个白痴，把她洗干净，客户是有品位的
And listen up, you moron - wash her up. The clients have taste.
她最近生过孩子会有什么问题吗？
Is it a problem if she recently gave birth?
听着，女人就是女人
Listen, the pussy's a pussy.
别再问我那些愚蠢的问题了
Stop asking me those stupid questions.
我们得在他问我怎么擦屁股之前离开
We need to go before he asks me how to wipe his ass.
医生! 你总是这么准时
Herr Doctor! Always on time.
那些德国佬把你教得很好，“博士先生”
Those Krauts taught you well, "Herr Doctor".
下午好，殿下，你今天好吗？
Good afternoon, Your Highness. How are you today?
我能说什么呢？
What can I say?
你知道在精神病院的日子是怎样的
You know how days in the nuthouse are.
你的医生告诉我有些轻微的好转
Your doctor told me there's has been a slight improvement.
好转，是的..
Improvement, yes. Yes...
- 请坐医生 - 谢谢
- Sit down, doctor, please. - Thank you.
- 白兰地? - 不是
- A brandy? - No.
- 这是你家乡井里的水 - 水？
- That's water from your well. - Water?
别这么小心翼翼，医生
Don't be so meticulous, Herr doctor.
如果我哥哥想毒死我，他早就下手了
If my brother wanted to poison me, he'd have done it a long time ago.
你还认为他们想毒死你吗？
You still think they wanted to poison you?
我不”认为”，我知道！
I don't "think", I know!
但是和一个死去的国王相比
But it's better to be a living patient
做一个活着的病人更好
than a dead prince.
谁知道呢
And who knows,
也许我这样对他们还有用
maybe I'll prove useful to them like this.
说到这，我的请愿书怎么样了？
Speaking of which, what happened with my petition?
什么请愿书？
What petition?
每月至少获准探访贝尔格莱德一次
To be allowed to visit Belgrade at least once a month.
陛下，这里什么都有
Your Majesty, you have everything here.
我哥哥真的那么无情吗？
Is my brother really so unmerciful?
他对我的惩罚还不够吗？
Didn't he punish me enough?
医生，请让我再去贝尔格莱德看看
Please doctor, let me see Belgrade one more time,
至少让我在普什维奇的坟墓上撒尿
at least to piss on Pashich's grave.
我会在这个笼子里腐烂的
I'll rot in this cage anyhow.
- 陛下，您需要休息 - 休息? ！
- Your Majesty, you need to rest. - To rest?!
- 找回本性，也可以这么说 - 你他妈的混蛋！
- To find yourself, so to speak. - You fucking prick!
- 是你把我弄到这里来的! - 不是这样的
- You were the one who put me here! - That's not true.
医疗小组认为您已经尽力了
The medical team decided that you should be committed.
一个由你领导的团队，阿瓦库莫维奇
A team led by you, Avakumovich.
你服从了我哥哥的命令
You obeyed my brother's orders,
还有那个日瓦科维奇混蛋的命令！
and the orders of that piece of shit, Zhivkovich!
冷静点，陛下，先生们！
Calm down, Your Highness, please. Gentlemen, gentlemen!
陛下... 我们已经讨论过了
Your Highness... We've already discussed this.
你的幻觉和妄想症
Your delusions and fantasies.
可能是由震惊导致的
They could be a consequence of shock.
- 甚至可能是你在战争中受的伤 - 你真是满口胡言！
- Maybe even your wound from war. - You're so full of shit!
我不是头部受伤，而是屁股受伤
I wasn't wounded in the head, but in my butt.
你回去告诉我哥
Tell that brother of mine...
那个疯子乔杰并没有完全疯掉
that crazy Djordje is not completely mad.
我要报仇雪恨
And that I'll get even
为他对我们的人民和我所做的一切
for all he had done to our people and to me,
那个卑鄙的家伙！
that lowlife scumbag!
我还有话要说！
I'll have the last word!
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
殿下... 谁知道谁还有话要说？
Your Highness... Who knows who'll have the last word?
冷静点，你需要放松
Calm down. You need to relax.
也许你的话会成为遗言
Maybe yours will be the last word.
那幅画叫什么名字来着？
What was the name of that painting, again?
黑色太阳
Black sun.
我喝不下了
I can't take this.
你必须喝，你整晚都在发烧
You have to. You had fever all night.
你不记得昨晚发生的事了，是吗？
You don't remember anything from last night, do you?
- 我记得你在这儿 - 没别的了吗？
- I remember that you were here. - Nothing else?
你把我和索尼娅搞混了
You had mistaken me with some Sonya.
别担心，我没有不尊重你
Don't worry, I didn't dishonour you.
只是一个小小的吻
It was just a little kiss.
你是不是把我和别人搞混了？
Did you mistaken me with someone?
你真是个怪人
You're weird.
我不怪，只是你不了解普通人
I'm not weird. It's just you don't understand how ordinary people are.
你上次和普通人说话是什么时候？
When was the last time you spoke with someone who's not rich?
哦，原来你仇富
Of course, you hate the rich.
不是这样的，只是..
That's not true. It's just...
每次我逮捕你们有钱人，上面就找我麻烦
They harass me every time I arrest one of you.
但是当我逮捕一个普通人的时候，没有人会大惊小怪
But when I arrest someone poor, nobody makes a fuss.
如果你觉得世道不公，为什么会选择做警察？
If you're tormented by injustice, why did you become a cop?
女士，你真的认为像我这样的人还有选择吗？
Lady, do you really think that guys like me have a choice?
美丽的小姐
My dear miss,
我们的生活就像赌桌上有记号的牌
our lives are like marked cards.
我们事先就知道我们会输掉这场游戏
We know beforehand that we're going to lose the game.
经过多年的战争和囚禁
What do you think, what else could I become
你认为除了警察
after years spent in trenches and captivity,
我还能干什么
than a city copper.
没有人强迫你为我们这样的人牺牲生命
Nobody is forcing you to sacrifice your life for someone like me.
但话又说回来..
But then again...
你不在乎为谁牺牲生命
You don't care whom you sacrifice your life for.
你唯一的目标就是尽快死去
Your only goal is to die, as soon as possible.
我已经死过一次了
I already died once.
什么？
Yes?
他们给我安排了一场葬礼
They arranged a funeral and all that.
这并不像有些人想的那么糟糕
It's not that bad as some may think.
- 你出老千? - 没，运气而已
You're getting fleeced, huh? - No luck.
我数学不好
No maths.
大家听我说，你们三个跟我走
Can I have your attention, please. Three of you are going with me
- 去亚塔汉贫民窟 - 你在开玩笑吧？
- to Yataghan slum. - You must be joking?
建国以来警察就没去过那里
The coppers haven't set foot there since the Ottoman times.
今天情况有变
Well, that changes today.
塔纳西耶维奇探长最后一次出现就在那里
Inspector Tanasiyevich was last seen there.
别担心，他们不会把他怎么样的
Don't worry. They won't touch him.
- 我们现在就走 - 等等！
- We're leaving now. - Wait!
这是命令！
That's an order!
车在哪儿？
Where's the car?
别开车，他们会把车砸成碎片的
Don't. They'll smash it into pieces.
好吧，我们步行去
All right, we'll go on foot.
快去，斯维塔，去拿枪！
C'mon, Sveta, give us the guns!
探长，请再考虑一下，这很危险
Inspector, please think about it one more time. It's risky.
你没有经验
You're inexperienced.
你以为你什么都能做，但是..
You think you can do anything, but...
警察! 警察！
Cops! Cops!
斯塔夫拉，警察来了！
Gezim, Stavra! Cops!
警察! 警察！
Cops! Cops!
- 安托，兄弟! 警察来了! - 怎么回事? 今天是什么日子？
- Anto, bro! The cops are coming! - How? What day is it?
我不知道! 是那个塔尼的小弟
I don't know! It's that Tane's kid.
- 警官，我们回去吧！- 你拒绝执行我的命令？
Oh, man... Inspector, let's go back. You refuse to carry out my order?
不是那样的，我怕我会死在这
It's not that. I'm going to leave my bones here.
- 我也是 - 安静！
- Me too. - Silence!
- 跟我来 - 散开！
- Follow me. - Spread out!
是那个跟玛拉上床的警察吗？
Is that the copper who shags our Mara?
大家下午好
Good afternoon, people.
塔尼还说要照看他，真是个白痴
Tane said to watch over him. He's a moron.
我要让那个婊子看看谁才是这里的老大！
I'll show that fucking whore who's the boss around here!
我们只是想问大家一些简单的问题
We just want to ask you some routine questions.
滚开! 回去！
Fuck off! Go back!
我要开枪了！
I'll shoot!
站住! 后退! 滚开！
Hold it right there! Go away! Fuck off!
你以为你在干什么? 把宪兵带到贫民窟来？
What do you think you're doing? Bringing gendarmes to the slum?
据我所知，警察可以去这个城市的任何地方
As far as I know, police can go to any part of the city.
不，你不能! 我们不遵守你们的法律！
No, you can't! We don't obey your laws!
去你妈的法律！
Fuck you and your laws!
你们的法律是议会里那些傻瓜投的票！
Those are voted by those fools in parliament!
这里是亚塔汉！
This is Yataghan, man!
- 你跟塔尼一个德行 - 我来这里就是要找他
- You're just like your Tane, man! - He's the reason I'm here.
- 他没去上班也不在家... - 他没事相信我
- He's not at work, not at home... - He's okay, trust me.
- 我不明白 - 相信我，他没事
- I don't understand. - Trust me, he's okay.
- 回你的警察局去 - 你不能这么跟我说话
- Go back to your headquarters. - You can't talk to me like that.
- 你知道我是谁吗? - 我知道，你是个白痴
- Do you know who I am? - I know. You're an idiot.
你还在等什么? 快走！日沃因！
What are you waiting for? Beat it! Zhivoyin, please!
- 我跟这事没关系! - 快把他带走！
- I've nothing to do with this! - Just get him the fuck out of here!
- 滚开! - 我要开枪了！
- C'mon, sod off! - I'll shoot!
- 住手! 住手! - 退后！
- Stop! Hold it! - Back off!
- 退后! - 过来
- Back off! - Come over here.
- 帕维里奇先生? - 是的
- Mr. Pavelich? - Yes.
- 给 - 谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
朱基奇先生在等你
Mr. Djukich is waiting for you.
法官大人，我真的不知道该说什么
Your Honour, I really don't know what to say.
当你选择国家的敌人作为律师时就是会发生这样的事情
That's what happens when you choose the enemy of the state as your lawyer.
那个无礼的叛国贼
That impertinent state wrecker.
我完全同意，但是最高层坚持
I couldn't agree more, but they insisted from the highest level.
朱基奇，求你了，别让我说出让我后悔的话
Djukich, please, don't make me say something I'll regret.
- 谢谢 - 请进
- Thank you. - Come in.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
世事难料
What can you do.
- 对不起，这里有人吗? - 请坐
- Excuse me, is this occupied? - Have a seat.
- 你太过分了帕维里奇 - 什么？
- This is outrageous, Pavelich. - What?
因为你愚蠢的表现，我们不得不延期审判
We had to adjourn the trial because of your frivolity.
更不用说往返监狱的交通费了！
Not to mention the costs of transport from prison and back!
下次听证会已经安排好了
The next hearing has been scheduled.
如果你再不出现
If you don't show up,
州政府会为你的委托人指派一名律师
the state will assign a lawyer to your client.
不用，我会去的
That won't be necessary. I'll be there on time.
我一定准时到场
The defendant will have a lawyer.
不需要指派律师
The assigned attorney won't be needed.
我再次道歉，谢谢你的理解
I apologise one more time. Thank you for your understanding.
我亲爱的州检察官
My dear state prosecutor,
你已经得到你想要的了
you got what you asked for.
早上好，你的病人呢？
Good morning. Where's your patient?
在马厩里，他已经站起来了
In the stables. He's on his feet already.
显然你已经给他热身了
You warmed him up good, apparently.
没药了，就在最痛的时候
I ran out of it, just when it hurts the most.
但是对于你，我总是有些东西
But for you, I always have something.
如果我们能给你找到一匹漂亮的母马
If we could find you some nice mare to play with.
我们会找到的，别担心，但是我们会付钱的
We'll find it, don't worry, but will have to pay for it.
在我们这个年纪，没有人愿意出于爱去做爱
At our age, no one want's to do it out of love.
我们出去兜兜风吧，就像以前一样
Let's go out for a ride, like in the old days.
小心点，他会咬你的
Be careful. He'll bite you.
他不会的，我已经身上有你的味道
He won't. I've picked your smell.
走吧，小马
Let's go, horsey.
你为什么不接受我的感激之情？
Why won't you accept my gratitude?
我可不能习惯别人的感激之情，走！
I mustn't get used to it. Come on!
在那匹马上，你看起来真像个白马王子
On that horse, you really look like prince charming.
谁骑马都像王子，驾！
Like horse, like prince. C'mon, horsey!